Abdullah Abutaleb

Montreal, QC Abdullah.3at@gmail.com 438-866-4638

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/abdullah-abutaleb

Portfolio: iabdullah.ca

Summary

I am an accomplished Full Stack Developer with a specialization in the MERN stack, experienced in enhancing
website user experiences and maintaining software products. My background as a dedicated Physical Therapist
has honed my skills in comprehensive patient care and data management. I possess strong analytical skills and
have a keen interest in data analysis, enabling me to provide a unique perspective on problem-solving and
decision-making. Additionally, my diverse interests, including trading, contribute to my well-rounded skill set.

Experience

Full Stack Developer

self employeed • Montreal, QC

12/2022 - Present

- · Redesigned the website to create a more visually appealing, user-friendly experience
- Maintained software products including programs, webpages, and databases
- Developed Font-End and Back-End By (MERN)

Quantitative Trader

Self Employed Contractor

01/2019 - Present

- · Analyze data using advanced statistical techniques and provide reports and visualizations
- Use software packages to analyze data and create visualizations

ADS - Covid Agent (PT - OT)

Ciusss • Montreal, QC

02/2022 - 04/2023

- Provided care to patients with physical disabilities through rehabilitative treatments
- · Educate patients on the effective use of wheelchairs, walkers, and other DME
- · Serviced hospital medical equipment

Co-Founder

Ladulla - Perfumes Brand • Jeddah, Mecca

02/2020 - 11/2022

- · Attended weekly meetings, collaborating with team members on goal implementation
- · Analyzed and controlled expenditures of the plant to conform to budgetary requirements
- Built relationships with customers to communicate issues and improvement suggestions

Physical Therapist

Saudi German Hospital • Jeddah, Mecca

02/2019 - 02/2020

- Collected and categorized patient data and recorded patient progress records
- Trained new physical therapist assistants in applying rehabilitation therapy
- Provided care to patients with physical disabilities through rehabilitative treatments

Skills

Communication skills, Computer skills, Care plans, Organizational skills, Python, Javascript, Data Analysis, Critical Thinking, Problem Solving, Research Skills, Teamwork, Machine Learning, Time management, Behavioral health

Education

Diploma in Full-Stack Web Development

Concordia University • Montreal, QC 05/2023

Physical Therapist

Batterjee Medical College • Jeddah, Mecca 02/2020